Josselin Francois-Downey

Software Developer

South East Melbourne, VIC • J 0439 187 701 •





jossfrancois@gmail.com





Objective

Strengthen my skills as a developer and contribute to projects that allow me to learn and grow my technical knowledge. I want to experience various aspects of software development in depth, I have a particular interest in website development but I am always keen to work on other types of tasks.

Skills

Finding efficient solutions quickly and adapting to any situation with a methodical approach.

Learning new concepts rapidly and researching them further, often in-depth, for my own understanding and to share with team members.

Always keen to learn and to be a versatile developer, while maintaining a strong and thorough knowledge of each aspect of my work.

Interests

Web development \(\text{UI/UX} \)

New technologies

Hardware concepts

Technologies



Languages

- · English Native/Bilingual
- French Native/Bilingual
- Spanish Working proficiency
- · Vietnamese Beginner

Profile

Experienced Full Stack developer with strong programming skills and an even stronger interest in design and user experience, with more than 4 years of industry experience in creating responsive, engaging and performant websites, having a key role in conceptualization, designing, coding, optimizing, and debugging

Passionate about website and software development and learning new notions and techniques, to continually improve and stay up to date with modern development concepts

Experience

Full Stack Developer • Deloitte Digital Tax • Nov 2021 - Present

- Working in depth with C# to create and maintain APIs as well as code a robust backend system that integrates with different Databases
- Using Azure products such as Azure DevOps, Azure Functions and Azure SQL
- · Coding in VBA and VB.NET to work on Office and Excel projects
- . Doing code reviews for clients, from project architecture and code analysis all the way to writing a comprehensive report

Full Stack Developer • Database Consultants Australia • Feb 2019 - Nov 2021

- Porting a website from ASPNET to Angular/C# with a renovated and responsive design, improving performance and user experience
- Following WCAG (AA) Guidelines and maintaining accessibility to a high standard in order to ensure the usability of the site and meet client requirements
- · Creating and maintaining an API to manage back-end/front-end communication
- Improving security by implementing OAuth2 and OIDC to manage user authentication and authorization
- Communicating directly with the client through Salesforce, fixing critical items in production
- · Working with SQL databases to optimize query speed and improve underlying architecture

Retail assistant • The Leaf Bookshop • Oct 2016 - Oct 2019

- Maintaining strong communication skills to ensure great customer experience
- Organize deliveries and returns of large quantities of books
- Running the shop independently, from opening time to closing the shop, including lock-up and cash-up

Education

Bachelor of IT • 2018 • RMIT University

- Algorithms and analysis
- Networking programming
- Exposure to Javascript
- Database concepts
- Software Engineering
- · Maths for advanced computing

VCE Equivalent (French Baccalaureate) • 2015 • Ste Anne d'Auray, France

· Graduated with honours

Projects

Discord bot using Python for University club

- Developing interactive commands and role management for users
- Hosting a service online using Heroku

Building a personal website (ongoing) using Next.js, tailwind

- Learning new frameworks and libraries
- Integrating with external APIs (GitHub, StackOverflow)